

✓ Konya, Turkey, TR✓ +905554443322✓ myinbox@gmail.com

myinbox@gmaii.com

safaorhan.com

in linkedin.com/in/safaorhan/

Introduction

This is Safa. I'm an **Android Developer & Trainer**.

I hold a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering and creating software for more than 12 years.

I've been developing Android apps since 2013 and making a living out of Android Development.

After graduating from the **top university** in my country, I've worked in startups, tech agencies and corporates and have written code that's been **used by millions and millions of people**.

I have a history of teaching software voluntarily and professionally $% \left\{ \left(1\right) \right\} =\left\{ \left(1\right) \right\}$

in **bootcamps**, **workshops**, **conferences** and **local events** for years.

I was working at Wayfair Berlin before I left my job to **teach people how to code** and how to become successful software engineers as a full-time job.

Work experience

Founder & Trainer June 2020

Cactus.School

I am creating educational materials and providing online classes to teach adults Android Development and Software Engineering principles.

I publish videos on my YouTube channel regularly and create online courses which are reachable via Udemy, Google Classroom and Caster.io

Android Engineer

October 2018 - June 2020

Wayfair Berlin

In the beginning I worked on the huge storefront mobile app of Wayfair which has **10M+ downloads** on Google Play along with **dozens of engineers**.

Then after our team in Berlin decoupled from the team in Boston I worked in a smaller team with and **increased pace** to create a new internal application to coordinate trade shows among teams in Wayfair.

Working with industry expert engineering managers and brilliant peers I learned a lot in terms of **building quality and sustainable software**, **architecting apps optimally** for different sizes of users / developers and create and **maintain a healthy and productive team culture**.

Android Trainer

March 2018 - July 2018

Re:Coded Istanbul Bootcamp

Re:Coded is a humanitarian organization which helps conflict-affected youth to become technology leaders of tomorrow.

I, as the Android Trainer of the Istanbul Bootcamp, follow Udacity & Google's Android Basics curriculum and teach adult students Android and Java.

Android Team Lead

May 2017 - May 2018

Bilgetech

I started my journey in Bilgetech as an Android Team Lead and got involved in managing projects and improving the team's development culture. I introduced API integration testing, CI and open source software

to the company.

Besides architecting and developing a handful of Android Apps we do for clients, I also published open source projects, published npm packages, wrote medium posts, gave technical talks and made youtube videos.

Founder 2016 - 2017

MobileMonsters

Founded a scalable mobile design & development team focused on startups. In MobileMonsters we designed and developed a handful of projects including Android, IOS, frontend and backend parts.

I managed the projects, arranged the clients, and did hands-on coding / designing when necessary.

Co-founder & Tech. Evangelist

2015 - 2017

Garaj.co

Garaj was formerly a makerspace, now a startup & tech community. I managed the tech community, gave talks, found speakers, organized events and built products for Garaj.

Head of Mobile 2016 - 2016

ErasmusInn (now studentinn.com)

I designed & developed ErasmusInn's Android application.

Android Developer

2015 - 2015

Sellsnap

Sellsnap was a second-hand goods marketplace. I renovated the Android app and developed some features.

Android Developer

2014 - 2015

Freelancer

Built Android apps as a freelancer.

Junior Android Developer

2013 - 2013

Metrekare

Metrekare was a real-estate marketplace startup that got funded from Aslanoba and EarlyBird Capital. The company was full of smart and award-winning people and inspiration is a daily routine of ours.

Junior Developer

2013 - 2013

Pergel

Pergel is an indoor navigation system that was being developed in Young Guru Academy's incubation.

Education

B.Sc. - Computer Engineering

2012 - 2017

Bogazici University

Bogazici is one of best universities of my country where professionalism, liberty and human rights are the fundamental principles. Computer Engineering department is full of competent students and valuable professors who are masterminds in their areas of study.

Voluntary Activities

Mobile Optimized Conf 2020

Conference Speaker

2020 - 2020

Droidcon EMEA 2020

I co-spoke at Droidcon EMEA which is the most prestigious conference in Android Development ecosystem.

Google LPW Istanbul Mentor

2017 - 2017

Google Türkiye

Google Launchpad Week is a mentorship program for startups. I helped numerous teams to improve their mobile products, get better at UX and follow a better mobile strategy.

Member of Advisory Board

2016 - 2018

Minizma

Minizma is a workshop programme for maker children lead by engineers and teachers. I provide the team with my insights about technology and startups.

Coder Ninja 2016 - 2016

Coder Dojo - Garaj

I helped kids aged 6-16 to learn and appreciate coding and hobby electronics using Scratch and Arduino. I introduce the world of software engineering to the kids and they fell in love with what they saw.

Skills

Android Development

I have experience in building big projects with best-practices. I have debugged, maintained, optimized and updated numerous Android projects.

Java Design Patterns

I know how to write clean, pragmatic and convenient code. I appreciate quality in code and have the mindset of a software craftsman.

Leadership

I have lead teams of developers multiple times, familiar with PM tools and have experience in budgeting and estimating software lifecycles.

UI / UX Design

I know how to use Sketchapp. I know where not to put that call to action button. I draw occasional illustrations and know what meaningful design is.

Hackathon Stack

I have built front-end and back-end applications for clients or for myself.

Tags: html, js, css, jquery, vuejs, node, express, deployd, RESTful services, nginx, ubuntu, digital ocean, arduino, raspberry pi, esp8266...

References

Said Tahsin Dane

Engineering Manager @ DeliveryHero +49 170 8887766

@tasomaniac

Christian Gross

Engineering Manager @ Wayfair Berlin +49 170 8887766

